[Music]
[音乐]
all right
好吧
my name is Billy Crandall you can find
我叫比利·克兰德尔（Billy Crandall）
me at villa Crandall and at William doc
我在别墅Crandall和威廉doc
Crandall at IBM so if you have any
IBM的Crandall，如果有的话
questions they don't get a chance to ask
他们没有机会问的问题
during this presentation or here
在此演示期间或此处
feel free to DMV or send me an email I
随时DMV或给我发送电子邮件我
will be more than happy to answer any
乐于回答任何问题
questions you have so of course this
您当然有这样的问题
presentation is collaborative contract
演示是协作合同
driven development so how many people
驱动发展，那么多少人
here are actually already doing contract
这实际上已经在签合同
urban development right now it's the
现在是城市发展
organization a couple few yeah of course
当然要组织几个
you know if that's kind of why you here
你知道那是为什么你在这里
to learn about it so that makes sense
了解它，这样才有意义
so let's get started one quick thing is
因此，让我们开始快速做一件事
IBM plow is a great place if you're
如果您愿意，IBM犁是一个好地方
needing to run your screen workloads we
需要运行您的屏幕工作负载，我们
have options you know if you're wearing
有选择，你知道你是否穿
spring boot course Apache Tomcat and if
spring boot 课程Apache Tomcat，如果
you're still running in the WebSphere or
您仍然在WebSphere中运行，或者
more Enterprise kind of war setting we
更多企业设置战争的方式
also have open Liberty so you can check
也有开放的自由，所以你可以检查
it out here also feel free to ask me any
在这里也可以随时问我
questions about IBM cloud but when
有关IBM Cloud的问题，但何时
you're really hear about is contract
你真的听说合同
driven development so let's just briefly
驱动开发，所以让我们简单地
kind of cover at a very high level what
很高的覆盖率
contract Urban Development is and we'll
合同城市发展是，我们将
get into it and more later
进入它，以后再说
just to kind of get your maybe head
只是为了让你的头
around this space so the point of
围绕这个空间，所以
contract of development is to define the
开发合同是为了定义
behavior of an API so a client is gonna
API的行为，以便客户端
send a call to service and that call is
发送服务电话，该电话是
gonna be like obviously a request and
显然就像一个请求，
it's gonna codes is some sort of end
代码会结束
point and is gonna have a good body
点，身体会很好
perhaps if it's you know a post or
也许如果您知道某个职位，或者
something like that it may not if it's
这样的事情，如果不是
like get all so many things have like
就像得到了那么多东西一样
headers but based upon that kind of
标头，但基于这种
request then the service assuming you
要求，然后假设您
know should respond in a certain way you
知道应该以某种方式回应
know there may be be a 200 response and
知道可能会有200条回复，
it's gonna have some amount of headers
它会有一些标题
and information within that contract
合同中的信息
driven development is when you actually
驱动开发是当您实际上
write this down in some sort of contract
用某种合同写下来
that can be actually programmed and
可以实际编程
tested against you're not just kind of
对你进行测试不只是一种
like writing down on paper or saying oh
喜欢在纸上写下来或说哦
yeah this is what this endpoints going
是的，这就是终点
to look like and then this is what it's
看起来像，然后就是这样
going to look like within the body and
看起来像在体内
you just kind of have to take care of
你只是需要照顾
iced word at it you
冰冷的话对你
actually can I have somebody can test
其实我可以有人可以测试
against so that way if there's like
反对这样的话，如果有
something like a small disagreement like
有点像小分歧
oh we did like a - instead of a
哦，我们确实喜欢-而不是
underscore for maybe like first name
下划线可能像名字一样
between the first and name in it you
在名字和名字之间
actually have somebody programmable that
实际上有人编程
will actually test the validate to make
将实际测试验证
sure it's actually matching what you
确保它实际上与您所匹配
agreed to so why should you care about
同意，所以你为什么要关心
this so obviously since many people only
很明显，因为只有很多人
a few people here are actually doing
这里实际上有几个人在做
contractor for development obviously
发展承包商显然
people are actually pushing an appoint
人们实际上是在推动任命
code to production right now without
现在无需生产即可生成代码
sets so why do you need to change why
设置，为什么你需要改变为什么
should you care about changing obviously
你是否应该在意明显的改变
I guess to some extent you're interested
我想你一定程度上有兴趣
in changing but one way I have always
在改变中，但我总是有一种方式
found about pushing changes or kind of
发现有关推动变化或某种
getting organizations to change is yet
尚未使组织发生变化
to kind of explain what is the current
有点解释当前是什么
problem with the way we're doing things
我们做事方式的问题
right now how can you be approved upon
现在如何批准您
and I kind of think about this scene
我有点想起这个场景
from It's Always Sunny in Philadelphia
来自费城的永远阳光明媚
one of the characters Charlie is seen
查理（Charlie）的角色之一
taking a bag of trash through the bar
通过酒吧拿一袋垃圾
and a couple other characters Mac and
和另外几个角色Mac和
Dennis stop them and ask you what he's
丹尼斯阻止他们，问你他是什么
gonna do with it and he says he's gonna
要去做，他说他要去
burn the trash and they're like no you
燃烧垃圾，他们就像没有你
shouldn't do that he's like well I can
不应该那样做，他会很好
either burn it where he become stars or
要么在他成为星星的地方燃烧它，要么
is gonna stay in the grounds going to be
会留在原地
there forever
永远存在
and because they don't really know
而且因为他们真的不知道
enough about you know trash and stars
关于你的足够了解垃圾和星星
and fire and stuff like that they can't
还有火和诸如此类的东西
really explain why he's wrong and so
真正解释他为什么错了等等
kind of in another way it's like oh you
有点像哦，你
made confidence presentation say like oh
信心十足的演讲就像哦
contractor of a development we should
开发的承包商，我们应该
really start doing this and you know a
真的开始这样做，你知道
manager or someone above you may be like
经理或您上方的某人可能像
wait why do we need to change what's
等待，为什么我们需要改变什么
wrong with like our current way of doing
像我们目前的做法那样是错误的
things this first part of this
事情的第一部分
presentation is going to kind of go
演示将进行
through some of that some scenarios that
在某些情况下
kind of maybe explain some of the
也许可以解释一些
problems and difficulties of not doing
不做的问题和困难
contractor faux developments so this
承包商的虚假发展
first one and I love to use gifts so
第一个，我喜欢用礼物，所以
we're gonna look at that and is it can
我们要去看看，可以吗
everybody kind of see that okay and it's
每个人都知道没关系，这是
gonna kind of have an idea of trying to
有点想尝试
communicate with an already existing
与已经存在的人交流
service that maybe doesn't have the best
可能没有最好的服务
documentation so we have a client and
文档，所以我们有一个客户
they need it connected a customer's a
他们需要它连接客户的
service to get customer information
获得客户信息的服务
and it's like okay well DG rethink
DG重新思考就好了
documentation they have a word doc okay
文档他们有一个单词doc可以
call get customers to get information
致电获取客户以获取信息
well they do that if they should be good
好吧，如果他们应该做的很好
but it's actually a post endpoint well
但这实际上是一个后期终结点
he said go get customers and not get
他说去得到顾客而不是得到
anything back oh four or five you should
任何东西回来哦，四五个你应该
have been using a post okay so he's now
一直在发帖，所以他现在
calling the post now still getting
现在打电话给帖子
nothing back
一无所有
well Diggs he sent the header for
Diggs他将标头发送给
authorization okay now he's sending
授权好了，他正在发送
everything
一切
Austin tracing the header up 500 error
奥斯汀跟踪标题向上500错误
what went wrong now well now the service
现在出了什么问题现在服务很好
is down because it's being brought down
之所以倒下是因为它被倒下了
for maintenance oh it gets back a 200 HT
维修哦，它恢复了200 HT
Pico but has an error and it he doesn't
笔克，但有一个错误，但他没有
know what if it means you know just some
知道这是否意味着您只知道一些
error code one two three known from
错误代码一二三
Mason about what it actually happens so
梅森关于它实际上发生了什么
what's going on here well we have a
这是怎么回事，我们有一个
poorly defined or undocumented API we
API定义不明确或未记录，我们
have inconsistent behaviors and patterns
行为和模式不一致
I mean not necessarily you have to use
我的意思是不必一定要使用
rest for everything but like it's not
休息一切，但事实并非如此
using verbs within the name instead of
在名称中使用动词代替
actually having that being HTTP so maybe
实际上是HTTP
it's doing it there but in another area
在那边做，但是在另一个地方
maybe is following proper restful
也许正在适当放松
protocol so you have potentially
协议，因此您可能
inconsistent behavior patterns and then
行为模式不一致，然后
also testing against a Live service can
还可以针对实时服务进行测试
lead to inconsistent results there's
导致结果不一致
been times I know where I was working in
曾经有一段时间我知道我在哪里工作
developing against some sort of new API
针对某种新API开发
and then like I think I finally have it
然后就像我想我终于拥有了
working I'm calling it correctly and I'm
工作，我叫正确，我
still getting failures and so I'm like
仍然有失败，所以我喜欢
looking through making may be something
仔细看可能是
wrong with my API or something you know
我的API或您知道的内容有误
set up incorrectly and maybe after two
设置不正确，可能在两个之后
days of working and trailing tracking
工作日和跟踪日
people down on what's going on to get
人们对即将发生的事情感到沮丧
like that person information on how it's
像那个人一样的信息
actually working I actually find out
实际工作，我真的发现了
that maybe that the service I was
那也许就是我所提供的服务
actually trying to call was misconfigure
实际上试图打电话是错误的配置
or something or I was down and so I just
还是什么，或者我很沮丧，所以我只是
wasted two days all because like a
浪费了两天，因为
service was down but I think we all have
服务下降，但我认为我们都有
kind of been here kind of judging by
有点像这里的评判
some of the laughs that we've tried
我们尝试过的一些笑声
working with api's and this is you had
使用api的，这就是你有
no idea how it works is because you're
不知道它如何工作是因为你
using like a PDF or Word document to
使用像PDF或Word文档
actually use it and that API the
实际使用它和该API
documentation was badly out of date
文档严重过时
because there's only updated and written
因为只有更新和书面的
once when it was first employees never
曾经是第一批员工
updated since so another problem with al
更新，因为铝的另一个问题
with not doing contract derivative
不做合约衍生品
relevant is you have a very serial path
相关的是你有一个非常串行的路径
to how you do production so you're
如何进行生产，以便
starting off like a new feature or new
像新功能或新功能一样开始
service or you may be adding a new
服务，否则您可能要添加新的
feature to a service and so you kind of
服务的特色，所以您有点
had all your design meetings and now you
参加了所有的设计会议，现在您
can actually get going
真的可以走了
but now you kind of have to wait on the
但现在您必须等待
service developer to actually build and
服务开发人员实际构建和
write that service so you're the client
编写该服务，使您成为客户
developer can actually start writing and
开发人员实际上可以开始编写并
doting against it and so what are some
反对它，所以有一些
of the problems with that well ok now
现在的问题还可以
service FL we're back there saying all
服务FL我们回到那里说了所有
right freeze while I get it ready
当我准备好时冻结
well clients like well is the ordinate
像这样的好客户是纵坐标
right II know how to make a change it's
正确的II知道如何做出改变
a you know a PI finalized no making a
你知道一个PI最终没有做出
model change or something like that and
模型变化或类似的东西
now this freeze and everything just got
现在冻结，一切都变得
pulled into a production issue and now
陷入生产问题，现在
that means all these features and stuff
这意味着所有这些功能和东西
you want to be working on as a client
您想成为客户
well it can't be done until that service
好吧，直到该服务才能完成
developer hasn't now a chance again to
开发人员现在不再有机会
continue doing their work again what's
继续做他们的工作是什么
going on here there's an inability to
继续这里无法
develop in parallel
并行发展
not until easily the service is at some
直到轻松地提供某种服务
sort of advanced stage can't really
那种高级阶段真的不能
begin right in I mean you could you
开始就在我的意思是你可以
could kind of do it may be a way of were
可能会这样做，可能是
you saying like hey this is what the API
你说就像嘿，这就是API
is going to look like and it's gonna
看起来像它会
look like these things but you can run
看起来像这些东西，但您可以运行
into those issues where this is maybe
这些问题可能是
slight variations on what it actually
实际情况略有不同
ends up looking like once the surface of
最终看起来就像
hope were actually rights it I know
希望实际上是正确的，我知道
again there's been times when generally
再次有些时候，一般
I'm on more the backend side of things
我更多地是在后端
where I'm like oh yeah it's gonna have
我在哪里，哦，是的
you know it's a person object because
你知道这是一个人的对象，因为
have first name last name middle name
有名字姓氏中间名
and so on and just how I actually named
等等，以及我实际的命名方式
those fields is maybe slightly different
这些领域可能略有不同
from what the client is expecting and
从客户的期望中
then we end up with this your timelines
那么我们就以此结束您的时间表
gonna be impacted by the ways from both
都会受到两种方式的影响
the service and client developers so
服务和客户开发人员
obviously we see there that that service
显然，我们看到那里的服务
developer gets pulled into some sort of
开发人员陷入某种困境
reduction issue and then that kind of
减少问题，然后
ways when the client developers can
客户开发人员可以使用的方式
continue working on it but then with the
继续努力，但随后
client developers maybe they can finally
客户开发人员也许他们最终可以
start working on it but then they get
开始研究它，但是他们得到了
pulled into a production issue or they
陷入生产问题或他们
have something else come up so you just
还有其他事情发生，所以你只是
you have a lot of potential delay
你有很多潜在的延迟
whereas if you have the ability to work
而如果你有工作能力
in parallel well then if once
并行好，如果一次
isolate the other monkey continued
隔离另一只猴子继续
progress while the other one catches up
进步，而另一个赶上
or is working on it as well and then
或正在对其进行处理，然后
also eventually the client developer
最终还是客户开发人员
maybe has to get up to speed so you had
也许必须加快速度，所以你不得不
all those design memes on how you're
所有这些关于你如何设计的模因
gonna actually work with and implement
实际与之合作并实施
the API but then it's like two weeks or
API，但大约需要两个星期
two months or who knows how long before
两个月或谁知道多久
that API is ready for you actually start
API已经为您准备好了
programming against it and all that
针对它以及所有其他内容进行编程
information you had in your head when
您何时拥有的信息
you're first going through those design
您首先要进行那些设计
meetings it's just completely gone now
会议，现在完全消失了
just because you've had a thousand other
只是因为你有一千个其他
things to do in the interim so you have
在过渡期间要做的事情
to take you know a week or so that's
让你知道一个星期左右
kind of remember like okay this is how
记得好吧，这就是
it's gonna actually work with this API
它实际上将与此API一起使用
and this is how it's gonna call this
这就是它的名字
endpoint and then build it into my
端点，然后将其构建到我的
system and finally we have the situation
系统，最后我们有了情况
okay you're working with an API out
好的，您正在使用API
there but it's also continuing and
在那里，但它还在继续，
continuing development and sometimes
持续发展，有时
maybe something changes about it
也许事情有所改变
so all sudden a service developer is
所以突然间服务开发者
like I'm gonna change this API get
就像我要更改此API一样
customers to customers default pup
客户对客户默认小狗
arrest but no one ever told the client
逮捕，但没人告诉客户
and it was deployed to production last
最后部署到生产
night and well now you're going to stay
晚上，现在你要留下来
late and oh wait also hate the custom
晚了哦，等等也讨厌这个习俗
role model is going to be changed as
角色模型将被更改为
well so hey have fun dealing with that
好吧，嘿，乐在其中
and why are they always the client of
为什么他们总是
ours the last person to hear about these
我们是最后一个了解这些的人
changes so again what's happening here
改变，所以这里再次发生了什么
well breaking API changes are not caught
未捕获到突破性的API更改
until they get to production you know of
直到他们投入生产为止
course you can't write integration tests
当然你不能写整合测试
but you kind of run into those problems
但是你碰到那些问题
I was talking about in the first present
我在第一个礼物中谈论
eight are the first scene where by
八个是第一个场景
relying upon live services you have the
依靠实时服务，您可以
issues where they can be down because of
他们可能会因为以下原因而陷入困境的问题
this configuration issues are they give
他们给这个配置问题
you the misconfigured or maybe the data
您配置错误或数据
that you're using to run your test it
您用来进行测试的
got changed or something so your test
被改变或其他东西，所以你的测试
you're not really believing in them when
你不是真的相信他们
they fail because it could be failing
他们失败了，因为它可能会失败
for a lot of reasons that really have
由于很多原因
nothing to do with what you're actually
与你的实际无关
testing before you actually put into
在实际投入之前进行测试
production and it works just fine
生产，并且效果很好
because the production services you know
因为您知道生产服务
are set up correctly and have all the
正确设置并具有所有
data you're kind of expecting so you
您所期望的数据，所以您
just kind of start ignoring like oh that
只是开始像这样
integration test failed
集成测试失败
who cares eventually after enough
谁在乎之后最终会在乎
failures and when it doesn't actually
失败以及何时不实际发生
mean anything you just start ignoring it
意味着什么，你只是开始忽略它
so you don't believe in it anymore
所以你不再相信它了
also the API change is heavily governed
API的更改也受到严格控制
by the service developer the service of
由服务开发者提供的服务
helpers is going to make a change to how
助手们将改变方式
the API looks that maybe best suits what
API看起来最适合什么
they feel like the API so it look like
他们觉得像API，所以看起来像
and so then the service of our decline
然后我们为衰落服务
developers to just have to kind of
开发人员只需要某种
accept that they don't really get a
接受他们并没有真正得到
whole lot of say and how it should look
大量的发言权以及它的外观
so hopefully that seems some relevant
所以希望这看起来有些相关
and that's kind of maybe I think three
这大概是我认为的三个
broad sand areas are kind of covering a
广阔的沙地覆盖了
lot of the problems with not doing
不做的很多问题
contract or development so let's start
合同或开发，所以让我们开始吧
digging in to see how contract driven
深入了解合同驱动
development actually can start resolving
开发实际上可以开始解决
these issues and for this we're gonna be
这些问题，为此，我们将
looking at spring cloud contracts so why
看着 Spring 的云收缩，为什么
swing call contact well actually for
秋千电话联系实际上很好
here I don't really need to explain it
在这里我真的不需要解释
we're all spring developers - presumably
我们都是春季开发人员-大概是
interested in using spring all the same
对使用spring完全感兴趣
it is a very actively develop project
这是一个非常积极的发展项目
actually a couple of a main developers
实际上是几个主要的开发者
on that project are in this presentation
该演示文稿中的内容
so I'm definitely not nervous at all
所以我一点也不紧张
about that it's also interoperable with
关于它还可以与
other tools and standards open API
其他工具和标准开放式API
packed really swagger there's like a
打包真的很招摇
plugin or library for it as well so if
插件或库，如果
you're already using these tools it's
您已经在使用这些工具了
not like you'd have to like throw it all
不像您必须喜欢全部扔掉
away in Petra learn something new you
在佩特拉（Petra）学习新的东西
can kind of go ahead and start using
可以继续使用
that your existing technology and maybe
你现有的技术，也许
migrate over just kind of keep it how it
迁移过去只是保持它如何
is all the same that interoperability is
互操作性是一样的
really nice
非常好
it also has flexible documentation on
它还具有灵活的文档
support with spring rest Docs so you can
支持Spring Rest文档，因此您可以
write out these contracts and from these
写出这些合同，并从中
contracts you can actually create some
合同您实际上可以创建一些
very nice-looking documentation for as
看起来非常漂亮的文档
well it's not you just have to look and
好吧，这不只是您必须看一下
understand these contracts you can
了解这些合同，您可以
create something that's very human
创造出非常人性化的东西
readable and finally and this is where
可读，最后，这就是
of course the collaborative part comes
当然合作的一部分来了
in it has polyglot supports and you can
它具有多语言支持，您可以
read more of it at this link so
在此链接上阅读更多内容，以便
initially when sprinkle contractors
最初在洒承包商时
first deployed are released you were
第一次部署的您被释放
writing contracts with groovy and this
与groovy签订合同
is kind of what a very simple contract
是一种非常简单的合同
would look like imagining you're calling
看起来像想像您在打电话
some sort of like person service and
某种类似的人服务和
you're adding a new one and you're
您要添加一个新的
getting to all one response back and
得到所有回应
with a header so anywhere that location
带有标头，以便在任何位置
should be so
应该是这样
pretty simple example of that and this
这个的非常简单的例子
has kind of gets back to the point of
有点回到
here's a request here's what it looks
这是一个请求，这是它的外观
like a post here's this URI and kind of
就像帖子一样，这里是这个URI和
what the content supposed to look like
内容应该是什么样的
and then here's what the response would
然后这就是回应
look like given this kind of request so
看起来像这样的要求
you have this contract written add new
您已将此合同写成添加新
person and then you can actually then
人，然后你实际上可以
run it against the service to see does
针对服务运行它以查看是否
the service given this actually
实际提供的服务
responded this way if it does great the
如果效果很好，则以这种方式回应
test pass of course you're not going to
测试通行证当然不会
have just no no meaningful API so it's
没有有意义的API，所以
going to have one contract in my
我要签一份合同
behavior with it you're gonna have a
与它的行为，你将有一个
bunch of different contracts all kind of
一堆不同的合同
explaining out how to use your service
解释如何使用您的服务
what happens when things okay what
当一切正常的时候会发生什么
happened when things so bad and so on
当事情如此糟糕等等时发生
when all these tests pass Part B or C
当所有这些测试通过B或C部分
ICD process they're eventually be built
ICD流程最终将被构建
and then bundle together into a stubs
然后捆绑成一个存根
artifacts and then that stubs artifact
工件，然后存根工件
can be put into your artifact repository
可以放入您的工件库中
so that it can be shared among your
以便可以在您之间共享
organization or whoever might be
组织或任何人
consuming your services so you know you
消费您的服务，以便您了解自己
can put it into a third party location
可以将其放入第三方位置
or a public location if you have some
或公共场所（如果有）
external vendors or external clients and
外部供应商或外部客户，以及
then finally those clients then instead
然后最后是那些客户
of having to test against your life
必须考验你的生活
service they can actually test against
他们可以实际测试的服务
this stubs artifact which is always
这个存根工件总是
going to give consistent results and
将给出一致的结果，并且
it's gonna also be much faster and so
它也会更快，所以
it's gonna you know if the client
你会知道客户是否
developers are using API correctly then
开发人员然后正确使用API
hopefully are their tests so to pass and
希望他们的测试能够通过并
of course also then you can actually
当然也可以
take all these contracts as mentions and
提及所有这些合同，并
then use it to create documentation that
然后用它来创建文档
can also then be shared with clients of
然后也可以与以下客户共享
how to use your API so that little
如何使用您的API这么少
colons a little bit off but the first
冒号有点脱落，但第一个
part the writing any contacts that's
分开写任何的联系方式
going to define a behavior and then the
要定义一个行为，然后
second you're gonna validate it third
第二，你要验证第三
you're gonna bundle and together several
你会捆绑在一起，几个
artifacts you've been you're going to
您去过的文物
test against it and they go to generate
测试它，他们去生成
documents and the that's second through
文档，这是第二个
fifth steps these should be part of your
第五步，这些应该是您的一部分
automated process so every time you're
自动化的过程，所以每次您
making a change and building your
做出改变并建立自己的
applications these tests are being run
这些测试正在运行的应用程序
so that
以便
way if something changes about the API
API发生变化的方式
some step is in this is gonna break
这是要打破的一步
early probably the first step are the
早期可能的第一步是
second step actually validating those
第二步实际验证那些
API matches and that's gonna prevent any
API匹配，这将防止任何
sort of unexpected changes to the API
对API的一些意外更改
from reaching production and it's also
从生产开始
always gonna make sure that your APR
总是要确保您的APR
your documentation is always up to date
您的文档始终是最新的
with whatever the API currently looks
无论API当前看起来如何
like all right but how are you gonna get
就像没事，但是你会如何
into this collaborating collaborative
进入这种协作式协作
process so service developers client if
流程，以便服务开发人员客户端
folks can actually really start working
人们实际上可以真正开始工作
together so right now you have like
在一起，所以现在你喜欢
producer during contracts if it's you
如果是您，则在合同期间制作
know a lot of times the front-end
很了解前端
clients they're gonna be PI JavaScript
他们将成为PI JavaScript的客户
developers writing your UI UX and like a
开发人员编写您的UI UX，就像
spa and this is all kind of with Java so
spa，这与Java差不多
really it's kind of maybe more producer
确实有点像制作人
driven contracts and the service is
驱动合同，服务是
telling you what the API looks like and
告诉您API的外观，
for the client this is still really
对于客户来说，这仍然是真的
great because they actually have some
很棒，因为他们实际上有一些
real nice contract they can actually
他们实际上可以签订的合同很好
program against that's also going always
反对的计划也总是在进行
give consistent results but another way
给出一致的结果，但是换一种方式
you can do this perhaps with maybe a
你可以用一个
more collaborative approach is
更协作的方法是
consumer-driven context as well and so
消费者驱动的环境
the client can explain hey this is what
客户可以解释嘿这是什么
I need from the service and now the
我需要服务，现在
service of ellebra is like oh okay yeah
ellebra的服务就像是
I can write this and then they can test
我可以写这个然后他们可以测试
against this contract and then
违反此合同，然后
eventually get something deployed out to
最终将一些东西部署到
production but why is collaboration
生产，但为什么要合作
importance well it gives you better
重要性很好，它可以使您更好
utilization of developer time whoever
谁利用开发人员时间
may have time right now to write these
现在可能有时间写这些
contracts they can be the one writing it
合同，他们可以成为写它的人
instead of all of it being on one side
而不是全都放在一边
you know whether it's a service
你知道这是否是一项服务
developer or the client developer more
开发人员或客户开发人员更多
input from all parties on the API design
各方对API设计的意见
so instead of just one having one
因此，而不是只有一个
opinion on what this API sir looked like
对这个API先生长什么样的看法
you can get both the consumers of this
你可以同时得到这个消费者
API and the producer itup I kind of
API和生产者版本
working together on designing what it
一起设计什么
should look like and hopefully this
应该看起来像，希望这
would leave more lead to more buy-in
会留下更多导致更多买入的机会
from all the parties on API design
来自各方的API设计
instead of it just being dictated to you
而不是仅仅由你决定
as a consumer you can actually have a
作为消费者，您实际上可以拥有
real say and how it also look however we
真实的话语以及它的外观，但是我们
can't spell collaborative without
没有合作就无法拼写协作
polyglot well
多声井
okay maybe cuz you can all the same
好吧，也许因为你们都一样
though it's not really gonna mean
虽然不是真的
anything unless you can actually allow
任何事情，除非您实际上可以允许
JavaScript developers to use tools of
JavaScript开发人员使用的工具
familiar with to write these contracts
熟悉撰写这些合同
without having to learn a whole new
无需学习全新的知识
stack so what are some language
堆栈，所以有些语言是什么
independent tools
独立工具
okay well Java developers JavaScript
好的Java开发人员JavaScript
developers and other developers you know
开发人员和您认识的其他开发人员
Java developers are obviously gonna have
Java开发人员显然将拥有
a JDK installed in the system so like
安装在系统中的JDK
they can build groovy contracts and so
他们可以建立常规合同，因此
on but JavaScript developers other
但是JavaScript开发人员其他
developers probably not maven are great
开发人员可能不是Maven很棒
all or whatever your build tool again
全部或其他构建工具
Java developers probably other
Java开发人员可能其他
developers and JavaScript developers
开发人员和JavaScript开发人员
know same as the Java friendly IDE so
知道与Java友好的IDE相同，所以
yeah you can see your problem here but
是的，你可以在这里看到你的问题，但是
docker
码头工人
who here has docker installed on their
谁在这里安装了码头工人
system yeah almost everyone so yes you
系统是的，几乎每个人，是的，你
know everyone's probably have docker or
知道每个人都可能有码头工人或
alesis language independence and of
aleles语言独立性和
course everyone's maker if they're a
当然每个人的创造者，如果他们是一个
developer they're gonna have a text
开发人员，他们将要发送文本
editor of some sort so that's really all
某种形式的编辑器，实际上就是全部
you need
你需要
so recently with the next last year so
所以最近跟去年
spring cloud contact is start allow the
Spring 云接触开始，允许
ability to write contracts in gamal yeah
可以用gamal写合同的能力
well you know sometimes the fact that
好吧，你有时知道一个事实，
you have whitespace may have a meaning
你有空格可能有意思
can be a little bit frustrating but it's
可能有点令人沮丧，但这是
also something that's completely
也完全是
independent of any specific language
独立于任何特定语言
platform JavaScript developers can write
平台JavaScript开发人员可以编写
this Java developers can write this
这个Java开发人员可以写这个
dotnet developers can write Yambol they
dotnet开发人员可以编写Yambol
can all right understand yeah Moe you're
可以了解你的意思吗
not gonna have to have learning a whole
不必学习整个
new stack to start writing this stuff
新的堆栈开始写这个东西
out so that contract I written wrote
出来，这样我写的合同写
earlier or sodor li ER in groovy this is
groovy中的早期或sodor li ER，这是
what the equivalent contact would look
等效联系人的外观
like in yam well so you can also see
就像在山药里一样，所以你也可以看到
that it doesn't get any more X's a
它不再得到X了
little bit less contract complex in many
在很多情况下合同复杂度降低
ways but it's not like you're taking
方式，但不像你在服用
some sort of like oh it's gonna be much
有点像哦，会很多
more harder to write it's useful more or
写起来更难，它很有用，或者
less just as easy and then we have some
少那么容易，然后我们有一些
docker images for reading and reading
用于读取和读取的docker映像
these contracts so be they encapsulate
这些合同，所以他们封装
all the Java and spring and logic within
所有的Java和spring以及其中的逻辑
the docker container so again all you
docker容器，所以再次
need is docker and there's images for
需要的是码头工人和有图像
both the consumer site and the producer
消费者站点和生产者站点
side and they can be configured by
侧面，它们可以通过配置
passing in
传递
environment variables I mean so kind of
我的意思是环境变量
how would work is if you're the client
如果您是客户，怎么办
you can just call this stalker mhm
你可以叫这个缠扰者
that's gonna be bringing in this Stubbs
这将带来这个斯塔布斯
artifact that we kind of taught about
我们教过的神器
earlier you can test to see if your
您可以较早地进行测试，看看您的
client will actually work against that
客户实际上会反对
and again that could be just a good if a
再一次，如果一个
stand-in against the actual live service
代替实际的现场服务
alternatively you can also have a docker
或者你也可以有一个码头工人
image bring in these contracts and then
形象带来这些合同，然后
test to make sure the service actually
测试以确保服务实际
works against this and again this can
与此相反，这可以
all be done just through docker so if
所有这些都是通过docker完成的，所以如果
you're maybe I know developer writing a
你可能是我知道开发人员写了一篇
no JavaScript service even you can kind
没有JavaScript服务，即使您可以
of work on this so you can work on it
为此工作，因此您可以对其进行工作
for both sites either client or producer
对于客户或生产者这两个站点
alright but let's actually see this
好的，但让我们实际来看一下
behavior in action listen I actually
实际行动中的行为听我说
talked about it so this is live coding
谈到它，所以这是实时编码
so this anyone want to be the sacrifices
所以这个人想成为牺牲者
something doesn't start working no hands
事情没有开始就没有双手
okay I'll just use a random bin all
好吧，我将全部使用随机垃圾箱
right so I am a Java developer through
对，所以我是一名Java开发人员
and through so this is a Java back-end
通过这是一个Java后端
and I'm just gonna be kind of using
我只是会有点用
postman to really interact with it but
邮递员与之互动
you can also but as far as how I'm gonna
你也可以，但就我要如何
be using spring cloud contract it's
正在使用Spring Cloud Contract
going to be entirely through just
将完全通过
language-independent
语言无关
tools docker and llam so anyways I have
工具docker和llamó所以无论如何我都有
this producer service that is serving up
这个生产者服务正在服务
produce and right now I just have a
生产，现在我只有一个
single get napping so I won't have to
单打n睡，所以我不必
spend so much time typing I just have
花很多时间打字
the other stuff currently commented out
其他东西目前已被注释掉
because really you're not here to see me
因为真的你不是来找我的
write out a restful service so get
写出一个宁静的服务，所以得到
mapping and it's just going to return a
映射，它只会返回一个
bunch of produce and so I had this
一堆农产品，所以我有这个
contract here right in an aunt llamo
在llamo姨妈那里订婚
just for the description of retrieving
仅用于描述检索
all produce and so it's gonna make a get
所有的产品，所以它会得到
call to API v1 and it's this large
调用API v1，它是如此之大
enough for everyone to see like even
足以让每个人看到甚至
weighing back good good ok great so it's
称重好好好好，所以
gonna call this API API v1 and given
将调用此API API v1并给出
this it should get a tuna response back
这应该得到金枪鱼的回应
and it's going to kind of return four
这将返回四
different items and it should also then
不同的项目，那么它也应该
have a header type of application JSON
具有应用程序JSON的标头类型
all right so let's actually see this in
好的，让我们实际来看一下
action
行动
oh sorry and then so then I have a
哦，抱歉，然后我有一个
couple of scripts and these are then
几个脚本，然后是
running the docker images so here's like
运行docker镜像，所以就像
the docker image spring cloud spring
docker镜像spring cloud spring
cloud contract and I'm using the most
云合同，我使用最多
recent release and just to kind of
最新版本，只是为了
quickly go over I'm saying to call the
快过去，我是说打电话给
application at this URL which is
该网址上的应用程序
actually my local machine I'm gonna
其实我要去的本地机器
publish the artifacts and then I'm just
发表文物，然后我只是
gonna give like the Navin coordinates as
会像Navin坐标那样给出
to what this artifacts will look like so
这些文物看起来像什么
producer service this should match with
生产者服务，应该与之匹配
the API service name and then what group
API服务名称，然后是什么组
it's going to be in or I can send those
它会在里面，或者我可以发送给那些
deploy to you for like our Sarat
像我们的Sarat一样部署给您
artifact repository and then I'm telling
工件存储库，然后我告诉
it where to read the contracts from and
它从哪里读取合同
then also the output from running the
然后还要运行
test so here I have my contracts and
测试，在这里我有我的合同，
right now I have just my find all
现在我只有我所有的
contracts I obviously have some other
合同我显然还有其他
contracts in here but there are
合同在这里但是有
currently different than Yambol so they
目前与Yambol不同，所以他们
won't be picked up and again retrieving
将不会被捡起并再次检索
all produce so let me get this producer
全部生产，让我得到这个生产商
service started here for some of my
我的一些服务从这里开始
scenes been signed and run kind of
场景已签名并运行
slower lately so take about 15 seconds
最近比较慢，大约需要15秒
to get it going
继续前进
so yeah just a normal spring boot
所以是普通的 spring boot
application
应用
one moments
一刻
just take that elf now
现在就带那个精灵
all right our application is up and
好吧，我们的应用程序启动了
running so I'm gonna take that existing
运行，所以我要利用现有的
on get all produce service and I'm gonna
继续获得所有农产品服务，我要
tell it to be gonna run a script to
告诉它要运行一个脚本来
validate it so now it's gonna spin up a
验证它，现在它将旋转一个
docker image it's gonna read in that
泊坞窗图片
contract and then it's gonna call that
合同，然后将其称为
service to make sure that its API
服务以确保其API
actually matches what is expected it
实际上符合预期
behaves in a way that's expected based
以预期的方式表现
upon that contract and why that runs so
根据那个合同，为什么会这样
if I call API v1 produce I'm gonna
如果我调用API v1产生，我将
expect back a response that looks like
期待回复看起来像
this and currently right now well that
现在，现在
runs so right now I can again also call
这样运行，现在我可以再次致电
this service and that's like the
这项服务，就像
response I'm gaining back okay it's just
回应，我回来了，好吧，只是
about done
即将完成
all right so yes all the tests passed as
好的，是的，所有测试都通过了
expected so now of course I am building
预期如此，所以我现在当然在建造
against this live service but I can run
反对这项现场服务，但我可以跑步
into issues you know again this service
遇到问题，您再次知道此服务
could go down like it could just bring
可能会像它带来的那样下去
it down myself
我自己
so we want to have something that it's
所以我们想要一些东西
always going to give us the same result
总是会给我们同样的结果
back so you can like set both run a
返回，因此您可以将两者都设置为
docker inmates to validate the contracts
码头囚犯确认合同
and validate the surfaces matching it
并验证匹配的曲面
you can run also in an image to actually
您也可以在图像中运行以实际
then read in that artifacts read in that
然后读入那个文物
stubs artifact they were building that
他们正在建立的存根工件
was built when we just ran that docker
是在我们刚运行该docker时构建的
build
建立
and so here what we're telling to do
所以这就是我们要告诉我们要做的
we're telling to go out and look in this
我们要出去看看
artifact repository once again if this
如果这再次出现工件库
is an artifact repository artifact
是工件存储库工件
repository running on my local machine
在本地计算机上运行的存储库
and it's gonna say look for this
会说找这个
producer service stubs artifact that we
生产者服务存根工件，我们
just built with this version and then
刚用此版本构建，然后
we're gonna run it on port nine eight
我们要在九号八号港口运行
seven six as the location to actually
七六作为实际位置
hit it for our Stubbs artifacts and
为我们的Stubbs文物击中它，
that's kind of here just kind of setting
在这里只是一种设置
up docker then to do that behavior all
码头工人然后做所有的行为
right so that's running so before heroes
对，所以在英雄面前跑
running on port 8080 but now if I
在端口8080上运行，但现在如果我
actually called the Stubbs ports I get
实际上叫做我得到的Stubbs端口
the same result back I get that every
同样的结果我得到每个
time so that's great and so the problem
时间，那很棒，所以问题出在
can be sometimes is like this data you
有时可能像这样的数据
can have it change all right so if I was
可以改变一切吗，如果我是
a restart this servers my running
重新启动此服务器，我正在运行
service and actually before we do that
服务，实际上在我们这样做之前
because it's slow
因为很慢
so there's a restart this service and we
所以有重新启动此服务，我们
call it again instead of just giving
再给它打电话，而不是仅仅给
four results back we're gonna get five
四个结果，我们将得到五个
through so it's because we added some
因为这是因为我们添加了一些
data to it which is work and you know
工作的数据，你知道
generally maybe kind of in this example
通常在这个例子中
maybe adding in another line of data
也许添加另一行数据
wouldn't be much of an issue but we can
不会有太大的问题，但我们可以
we've all run into those problems where
我们都遇到了那些问题
you have like maybe some automated test
您可能需要一些自动化测试
running and like the existing test data
运行并喜欢现有的测试数据
has changed in some way removed values
以某种方式更改了删除的值
changed and now those previous automates
改变了，现在那些以前的自动化
as we had running or something to fail
因为我们跑步或出现故障
because of that change in behavior or
由于行为的改变或
that change in data so yes we call this
数据的变化，所以我们称之为
so we call this again and yet now we're
所以我们再次称呼它，但是现在我们
getting back five results of course so
当然会得到五个结果
that they can change and data can just
他们可以改变而数据可以
make it very difficult to write
很难写
automated tests around but if this was a
自动测试，但是如果这是一个
fail it's not failing because something
失败，这不是失败，因为
actually changed and how the behavior
实际发生变化以及行为如何
works we just added some more data so we
我们只添加了一些数据，所以我们
can continue adding some more contracts
可以继续添加更多合同
so
所以
so we're going to add another contract
所以我们要添加另一个合同
of finding by a specific name of produce
通过特定产品名称查找
we'll stop the stubs service for now we
我们现在将停止存根服务
validate again and it should work
再次验证，它应该可以工作
but actually so right now I also
但实际上现在我也
uncommented it out that other get in
取消评论，其他进来
points where if you write a contract for
指出如果您为
something that's not yet there it should
尚不存在的东西
fail because that means the API doesn't
失败，因为这意味着API不会
actually do that behavior so once this
实际上就是这样做，所以一旦
runs will kick this off again
跑步将再次拉开序幕
oh that's not good so one thing is nice
哦，那不好，所以一件事很好
and Everly failures will happen that's
而且每一次失败都会发生
just kind of the way programming goes
只是编程的一种方式
and there is a really nice way you can
有一种非常好的方法
actually go and see the results of your
实际去看看你的结果
test okay so it picks up the fact I
测试还好，所以它可以理解我的事实
uncomment it out that ad produce and the
取消注释该广告产品和
reason it failed is because that API are
失败的原因是因为该API
we don't have a post endpoint available
我们没有发布终点
at that API so returns a four or five
在该API上，因此返回4或5
saying hey your API does not actually
说嘿，您的API实际上并没有
match the contacts you have available so
匹配您有空的联系人
be uncomment this out again we execute
取消注释，再次执行
these at all pass
这些都过去了
basically start to build up an API he
基本上开始建立一个API他
gets us consistent behavior they it's
让我们保持一致的行为
always gonna match what you're expecting
总是会符合您的期望
it to do if you have contracts that are
如果您的合同是
out there that the API doesn't yet
那里的API还没有
implement its gonna notice it and it's
实施它会注意到它的
going to cause the test to fail so that
将导致测试失败，从而
way if you have it part of any of your
方式，如果你有它的任何一部分
pipeline process running these automated
运行这些自动化的管道过程
tests you're not gonna get like in that
测试你不会像那样
third scenario some sort of test out
第三种情况进行某种测试
there that does not yet match that
那里还不匹配
behavior of course
当然的行为
oh I didn't restart of my boot service
哦，我没有重启我的启动服务
alright let's run it one more time
好吧，让我们再运行一​​次
should work
应该管用
so well that runs we're gonna kind of
运行的很好，我们将会
look this a little bit ahead on this so
向前看这个，所以
you also want sign some flexibility
您还想要一些灵活性
perhaps in what your inputs are and
也许在您的输入中
we're gonna take a look at here in just
我们将在这里看看
a moment because sometimes it's a
片刻，因为有时是
specific data that's necessarily matter
必不可少的特定数据
so much as it kind of matches with a
就像它与一个
certain ecstatic pattern of what you're
你的某些狂喜模式
looking for and we kind of see why that
寻找，我们有点明白为什么
could be very helpful in just a moment
片刻可能会很有帮助
so okay all those tests pass and so now
好吧，所有这些测试都通过了，所以现在
if I was then to take in that new stubs
如果我当时要接受那些新的存根
artifact that was just generated after
之后产生的工件
all these tests run okay that stubs
所有这些测试都可以进行
service is already up so if I call here
服务已经开通，所以如果我在这里打电话
8080 with this post endpoint everything
8080具有此发布端点的一切
passes I get back a 200 back here now if
通过，我现在回到这里200
I call nine eight seven six with that I
我叫九八七六
get back a 404 not found and the reason
找回404未找到的原因
why it says the content type doesn't
为什么说内容类型不
match exactly eight application JSON
完全匹配八个应用程序JSON
charts at UofT a with what I actually
UofT上的图表与我的实际情况
wrote in this contract so here I wrote
写在这份合同上，所以我在这里写
it has to be application this is what
它必须是应用程序，这是什么
the header should be because I didn't
标头应该是因为我没有
match it failed so we can actually add
匹配失败，所以我们实际上可以添加
some flexibility to this so I'm still
对此有一些灵活性，所以我仍然
gonna write in the contract that this is
要在合同中写明这是
what it should look like but I can then
它应该是什么样子，但是我可以
write matchers here to say well as long
写匹配器在这里说好
as it starts with application JSON
因为它以应用程序JSON开头
that's all that really matters
这才是真正重要的
similarly you know it doesn't does it
同样，您知道它不会
always have to be Kiwi that we sinned in
总是要成为我们犯罪的猕猴桃
well no not really but as long as it is
好吧，不是，不是，只要是
an alphanumeric value in there okay that
那里的字母数字值可以
is fine
很好
similar with quantity it doesn't have to
与数量相似，不必
always be 75 because that's not actually
总是75，因为那实际上不是
how things work we just need it to be at
事情如何运作，我们只需要它在
least one or more
至少一个或多个
numbers that are put in there and it has
放在那里的数字
to be numeric and similarly with the
是数字的，并且与
body of the response it doesn't always
响应主体并不总是
have to be this ID of ten that's
必须是这个ID十
returned this the ID has to be numeric
返回此ID必须是数字
in case we had some more values added in
万一我们增加了更多的价值
there so if we were to be comment out
在那里，如果我们要发表评论
this old one and comment this one in
这个旧的，并在此发表评论
so then this again should pass without
所以这应该再次通过
issue and while that's passing so in
问题，而那是过去了
this case so far I've always had a sown
到目前为止，我一直都在播种
hey I'm giving you some good examples of
嘿，我给你一些很好的例子
data and then you give me back a 200
数据，然后您还给我200
response but explain cloud contract
回应但解释云合约
isn't narrowly or built around only
并非狭narrow或仅围绕
handling when things so good you need to
处理好事情时需要
also define what happens when some a
还定义了一些
client miss uses your API so here the
客户小姐使用您的API，因此这里
field name is required but I forgot to
字段名称为必填项，但我忘记了
put it so in this example then instead
把它放在这个例子中然后
of sending back a 200 response I'm so
发回200的回复我是如此
suspense send back a 400 err response
悬念发回400 err回应
and then within the body it's gonna be
然后在体内
then error message instead of what a
然后错误信息，而不是什么
normal body would look like for adding a
正常的身体看起来像添加一个
new produce and it's just going to say
新产品，这只是说
missing required value of course this is
当然缺少所需的值是
extremely simplified but it could be
极其简化，但可能是
expanded upon to kind of handle whatever
扩展到某种处理任何
it might make sense then for your
那可能对你有意义
service so me going here comment this
服务，所以我去这里评论
one
一
and so then yeah I just and now just
所以是的，我只是现在
calm down to a service instead of
冷静下来而不是服务
directly to the repo and this just been
直接到回购，这只是
checking those fields to make sure
检查这些字段以确保
they're all correct and if they're not
他们都是正确的，如果不是的话
it's gonna then throw this client
然后要扔这个客户
exception which isn't caught by this
没有被这个捕获的异常
exception handler and in that case is
异常处理程序，在这种情况下是
going to return a bad request with the
将与一起返回错误的请求
error message and so for the previous
错误消息，对于上一个
example also our tests still passed
例子，我们的测试仍然通过了
after updating the contract and then
更新合同后，然后
let's add this last contract in for this
让我们为此添加最后一个合同
and then run it one more time oh thank
然后再运行一次哦，谢谢
you
您
I think we got the app of start yes earn
我认为我们已经有了开始的应用程序，是赚
enough before it was tested and so I
在测试之前就足够了，所以我
think we might be so good so thank you
认为我们可能很好，所以谢谢
for that yeah
为此
so everything passed and now like I said
所以一切都过去了，现在就像我说的
I'm a Java developer through and through
我是一名Java开发人员
I get kind of angry when I have to look
我不得不看的时候有点生气
at JavaScript so I know I'm using
在JavaScript，所以我知道我在使用
postman but you can also of course if
邮递员，但如果
this was like a JavaScript application
这就像一个JavaScript应用程序
you could be using that to test against
你可能会用它来测试
this as well so we'll just run the mock
这个也一样，所以我们将运行模拟
producer service
生产者服务
and that is all running and we're again
这一切都在运行，我们再次
once again hitting against this Stubbs
再次碰到这个Stubbs
API and if we send her response oh yeah
API，如果我们发送她的回复哦，是的
there we go
我们去
and of course also if we were to take
当然，如果我们要
this out where it's where there is no
这就是没有的地方
name it's gonna not send back a 200
名称它不会寄回200
response that's not right yeah well not
回答不正确是的，不是
sure what went wrong there - never done
确定哪里出了问题-从来没有做过
that let me see what happens against the
让我看看会发生什么
real API well they really be always
真正的API很好，它们一直都是
working alright I didn't see what's
工作正常，我没看到什么
wrong there I should have returned a 400
错了，我应该退回400
response I think there's an issue with
回应，我认为有一个问题
some of the matching and how it goes on
一些匹配以及它如何进行
I'll get that fixed within my
我会解决这个问题
application here anyways though with
无论如何在这里申请
contract defined services let's kind of
合同定义的服务让我们有点
go back to these scenarios I talked
回到我所说的这些情况
about this start of the presentation so
关于这次演讲的开始
you're not going to kind of run into
你不会碰到
these issues your API to me
这些向我发出您的API
automatically document as part of the
自动作为文档的一部分
process the accurate documentation
处理准确的文档
encourages this discussing then on
鼓励这种讨论然后
design consistency within your API and
API中的设计一致性，以及
also your clients can develop and test
您的客户也可以开发和测试
against these contracts that give
这些合同给
consistent results so you can have more
一致的结果，因此您可以获得更多
faith in your automated tests to serial
相信您对序列的自动化测试
development now you can have clients and
发展，现在您可以拥有客户和
service developers they can work in
他们可以工作的服务开发人员
parallel once the contract is written
合同签订后平行
you're not having to wait for our whole
您不必等待我们的整个过程
service to be built out this process
将在此过程中建立的服务
again encourages discussion on the API
再次鼓励有关API的讨论
design since you kind of have that all
设计，因为您拥有全部
just talked about in real time as to
刚刚关于
building it out altering the API the API
通过更改API来构建它
is going to be checked now as every time
现在将要每次检查
as far as a build process so if someone
就构建过程而言，如果有人
makes a change to how the API looks it's
改变了API的外观
gonna fail as we kind saw during my demo
就像我们在演示中看到的那样会失败
if I have a contract and the API doesn't
如果我有合同而API没有
actually match what that contract is
实际匹配该合同是什么
doing that
那样做
Tessa's the man gonna fail I kind of
泰莎的男人会失败，我有点
said we're other cause either the client
说我们是其他原因，无论是客户
or service' fails so also like let's say
或服务失败，所以也可以说
the contract and so on has been updated
合同等已更新
then the client hasn't been updated to
则客户端尚未更新为
consume it the clients test will fail
使用它，客户端测试将失败
when he's trying to test against that
当他试图对此进行测试时
the stubs artifact and so this prevents
存根工件，所以这可以防止
rogue changes from game production where
流氓从游戏制作中发生的变化
they can maybe sometimes become
他们有时可能会变成
finalized because usually it's easy to
最终确定，因为通常很容易
roll forward than it is to roll back so
前滚而不是后滚
a change that maybe no one really wanted
也许没人真正想要的改变
is all sudden now the way things will
现在一切都会突然发生
look in production going forward just a
展望未来的生产
few final points so in this example all
最后一点，所以在本例中全部
I sewed was rest in HTTP but you can
我缝在HTTP上休息，但你可以
also use spring cloud contract for
也将Spring Cloud Contract用于
writing for doing messaging talking this
为做消息而写作
it are not just Kafka but any kind of
不只是卡夫卡，还有任何一种
messaging it's flexible enough to do
消息传递它足够灵活
that it's also we hear contracts and so
也是我们听到合同等等
we think you can't change it like that's
我们认为您无法像那样改变它
breaking the contract but of course
违约但当然
always okay to change the contracts as
总是可以将合同更改为
the API changes and updates through time
API会随着时间变化和更新
contract tests are should not be
合同测试不应该
considered acceptance tests and are
被认为是验收测试，并且
neither replaces sort of into n tests
都没有取代n种测试
they're just part of your test suite
它们只是您的测试套件的一部分
you're not gonna be able to test things
你将无法测试事物
like resiliency time-out performance
像弹性超时性能
Ed's cases and so on you don't need
埃德的案件，等等，您不需要
these others kinds of tests but you're
这些其他类型的测试，但您
gonna be able to kind of make those
将能够使那些
integration tests a whole lot easier and
集成测试要容易得多，并且
whole lot quicker to run anyway stick
整个运行起来反而更快
around for some Q&amp;A and the code I
围绕一些问答和代码我
showed here it's not quite out there but
显示这里不是很远但是
when it is when I push it have to clean
当我推的时候它必须清洁
it up a little bit it's gonna be at that
它会在那一点
URL and there's some great documentation
URL，还有一些很棒的文档
of course where I just kind of basically
当然，我只是在某种程度上
take all the information write it and a
把所有的信息写出来，然后
lot of this presentation is actually
实际上，这个演示文稿很多
based upon this blog article from early
根据早期的这篇博客文章
last year and once again you can find me
去年又一次你可以找到我
at Billy Crandall on Twitter and email
在Twitter和电子邮件上的Billy Crandall
me at 1:00 Crandall at IBM and happy to
我在IBM Crandall的1:00，很高兴
answer any questions yes
回答任何问题是
if this contracts would live in a single
如果这份合同可以单人住
repository or in every repository for a
存储库或每个存储库中的
service or a client and how it would be
服务或客户，情况如何
organized in the CI CD pipeline so yeah
在CI CD管道中组织，所以是的
you could put them in like a separate
您可以像单独放置它们一样
repository where you can pull them down
您可以在其中删除它们的存储库
to read from or you can like having be
可以阅读或喜欢
stored like on a service like it's
像存储在这样的服务上一样
there's a different options to read from
有不同的选项可供阅读
but yeah you would then include this as
但是，是的，您可以将其作为
far as you like your CI v CI CD process
只要您喜欢CI v CI CD流程
that's something I'm planning on
我正在计划
continuing adding on to this
继续添加到此
presentation to kind of so how you would
演示，以此类推
really incorporate this into like a CID
真正将其纳入CID
CI CD pipeline yeah other questions how
CI CD管道是的，其他问题如何
do you when you're defining a contract
您在定义合同时会做什么？
how do you define the set up for a test
您如何定义测试设置
so for example in this contract the
例如，在本合同中，
server must have returned for four
服务器必须返回四个
objects yeah how do you define the you
对象是的，你如何定义你
know actions that needed to be done like
知道需要做的动作，例如
inserts to a database or some end points
插入数据库或某些端点
heated before the test yeah server
在测试服务器之前加热
returns these four objects
返回这四个对象
yes so in this example I was hitting
是的，所以在这个例子中
against the live surface now in a more
现在更贴近实况
realistic example you would have all
现实的例子，你将拥有所有
that underlying behavior mocked out so
基础行为被嘲笑了
like you know exactly what's gonna get
就像你确切知道会得到什么
initially returned so as you're actually
最初返回是因为您实际上
initially writing out those contracts
最初写那些合同
they're gonna pass so how you would do
他们会过去，所以你会怎么做
that in the real world is you just have
在现实世界中，你只是拥有
underlying mocked out behavior when
潜在的嘲笑行为
you're actually calling out that that's
你实际上是在说那是
those tests so
这些测试是这样的
yeah
是的
so talking about the real world again do
所以再次谈论现实世界
you keep versioning of the same contract
您保留同一合同的版本控制
or do you replace the same contract
还是您替换相同的合同
again and again because sometimes you
一次又一次，因为有时你
want to keep two versions running in
想保持两个版本运行
parallel of the same endpoint of the API
与API的同一端点平行
in production so how you would really
在生产中，所以你会如何真正
probably want to do that is kind of like
可能想要这样做就像
this within the URL of your API you
在您的API网址中
would have like a v1 or v2 and so on so
会喜欢v1或v2，依此类推
that's how how you would actually handle
这就是您实际处理方式
that kind of versioning so you would
这种版本控制，所以您会
have two different fights yeah you would
有两次不同的战斗，是的，
then have to have a separate contract
然后必须有一份单独的合同
written out because this contract is
之所以写出来，是因为这份合同是
still pointing to v1 so maybe you would
仍然指向v1，所以也许您会
then update this contract to maybe be v1
然后将此合同更新为v1
or you probably always have it be v1
否则您可能永远都是v1
when you're renting out and you would
当您出租时，您会
still want this contract obviously out
仍然希望这份合同明显退出
there and being tested against so long
在那里，经过了很长时间的测试
as that API is still alive in public
因为该API仍在公共场合
because you're still obviously
因为你仍然很明显
supporting at that time
当时的支持
and again you know I'll see if you have
再一次，你知道我会看看你是否有
a question later on for you frill name
稍后给您一个简单的问题
your question also we have some of the
您的问题也有一些
experts far more knowledgeable and
专家知识渊博，
streetcar contract in here as well so
这里的有轨电车合同也是如此
thank you
谢谢
[Applause]
[掌声]
[Music]
[音乐]